NHI CHUNG

Email: nhibchung@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nhichung Web portfolio: http://nhibchung.github.io

SUMMARY

Software engineer with experience working at startups, video game, AR/VR, and geospatial technologies. Fast-learner, adaptable, analytical, and detail oriented self-starter with a passion for learning; able to prioritize effectively to accomplish multiple tasks with creativity and stay calm under pressure.

SKILLS

Technical

- Working knowledge of C# (Unity), C++, Java, video games, AR/VR, Unity, Oculus
- Experience with GIS, remote sensing, mapping APIs (Mapbox, Carto, Google Map)
- Familiar with Agile, Scrum, Git, PlasticSCM, Jira

EDUCATION

Aug 2016 - May 2018 California State University, Fullerton

Fullerton, CA

Master of Science in Software Engineering (MSE) - GPA 3.83

Sep 2013 - Jun 2015

University of California, Santa Barbara

Santa Barbara, CA

Bachelor's Degree in Geography - Geographic Information Science (GIS) - GPA 3.66

Dean's Honors: UCSB Winter 2015, Spring 2015

EXPERIENCE

Mar 2021 - Present

HAVIK

Remote (US)

Software Engineer

- Develop AR & VR simulations for military training using Unity game engine
- Implement new networking, communication, and user management features using C#,
 Unity, and open source libraries
- Create prototypes for experimental features, apps, and Unity plugins

Jul 2019 - May 2020

NextVR

Newport Beach, CA

Rapid Prototype Engineer

- Use Swift and AVFoundation to create an iOS application that synchronizes multiple cameras for stereoscopic capture
- Integrate new functionalities into in-house game engine for VR using C++
- Utilize open source API/SDK to: access VR hardware (OpenVR), render 3D graphics (OpenGL), and play audio for in-house game engine development
- Use Unity game engine to develop prototypes for AR/VR platforms

Dec 2018 - Jun 2019

Motion Scientific

Greater Los Angeles Area

R&D Software Engineer: Augmented Reality

- Start-up funded by the National Science Foundation (Phase I)
- Research and develop an augmented reality (AR) application for physical rehabilitation
- Utilize Unity, Tensorflow and other technologies for Android and iOS development

Jun 2018 - Nov 2018

Boeing

Huntington Beach, CA

Software Engineer II

- · Assist with the development, testing, documentation and maintenance of software systems
- Work on Java database migration and Unity game engine for HoloLens development

PROJECTS

Matching Cards Game

- A simple card game created with Unity for WebGL that can be played in a browser.
- This project was for me to learn more about using design patterns in Unity.
- Check out the project on my Github page.
- Project demo link: https://nhibchung.github.io/project/matchingCards/index.html

Helicopter Simulation Oculus VR Game

- Created with Unity3D, C#, and WRLD SDK(3D maps based on real-world coordinates)
- Gameplay includes piloting the helicopter to waypoints following a navigational arrows
- Project link: https://nhibchung.github.io/project/helicopterVR/helicopterVR.html

Poke-A-Mole Augmented Reality(AR) Game

- AR game created with Unity3D, C#, and Vuforia AR Groundplane
- Project link: https://nhibchung.github.io/project/pokeAMoleAR/pokeAMoleAR.html

Oculus Rift VR Exploration Game

- Immersive VR game level created with Unity3D in C#
- Uses the Oculus Avatar SDK hand features for Touch to interact with the environment
- Project link: http://nhibchung.github.io/project/oculusExploration/oculusExploration.html

VR Labyrinth for Android Google Cardboard – based on a Udacity project

- VR game created with Unity3D in C#
- Project link: http://nhibchung.github.io/project/vrLabyrinth/vrLabyrinth.html

Interactive Solar System created with Unity3D Game Engine

- 3D browser-based WebGL Solar System application with clickable objects and minimap
- The sun and all planetary objects created using NASA images
- Project demo link: http://nhibchung.github.io/project/solarSystem

GIS Group Poster Presentation – Course Project

- Used Java and Twitter API to gather geotagged tweets containing 6 popular presidential candidates to make predictions for the 2016 elections
- Compared data with polls, performed sentimental analysis using the Stanford NLP API
- Poster Link: http://nhibchung.github.io/project/gisPoster.pdf

COURSES

University of California, Santa Barbara

Python - Intro to Computer Science (CMPSC 8)

C - Problem Solving I (CMPSC 16)

C++ - Problem Solving II (CMPSC 24)

Java - Conceptual Modeling and Programming for the Geo-Sciences (GEOG 178)

Analytical & Computer Cartography - Web Mapping with JavaScript, HTML5, CSS (GEOG 128)

Calculus with Applications 2 (MATH 3B)

Linear Algebra with Applications (MATH 4A)

California State University, Fullerton

Systems and Software Standards and Requirements (CPSC 541)

Software Verification and Validation (CPSC 542)

Software Maintenance (CPSC 543)

Advanced Software Process (CPSC 544)

Software Design & Architecture (CPSC 545)

Independent Coursework

Saylor Academy - Elementary Data Structures (CS 201)

Udacity courses - Introduction to Virtual Reality, VR Scenes & Objects, VR Software Development (Note: please visit LinkedIn for a complete list of courses)